<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>emdwyer</title><link>https://emdwyer.github.io/</link><description>emdwyer's personal site - development, infosec, security</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>hello@emdwyer.dev (emdwyer)</managingEditor><webMaster>hello@emdwyer.dev (emdwyer)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://emdwyer.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Current Dev Setup and Activity</title><link>https://emdwyer.github.io/2021-03-28-learning-update/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>emdwyer</author><guid>https://emdwyer.github.io/2021-03-28-learning-update/</guid><description><![CDATA[My current setup The last several months have seen me moving around.. A lot (thanks COVID).. But after hunting around for furniture due to a shortage of standing desks, I&rsquo;ve finalised my setup &ndash; and thank god.
Setup It&rsquo;s been great to revive my Ultrawide and laptop in a fairly minimalist setup. This is my primary dev machine which, if you see my GitHub, has caused no end of issues with running Linux (#YearOfTheLinuxDesktop) in the 2 years I&rsquo;ve had it.]]></description></item><item><title>Rebuilding Homelab - Part 1</title><link>https://emdwyer.github.io/2021-03-24-rebuilding-homelab/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>emdwyer</author><guid>https://emdwyer.github.io/2021-03-24-rebuilding-homelab/</guid><description>Cable management - please don't do this. Ever. After relocating around Melbourne multiple times during 2020 (pandemic - long story) and finally settling into my own place with FTTC, I decided it was time to revive the home lab. Previously back in Newcastle, my homelab comprised of:
HP MicroServer Gen 8 (running Proxmox) HP ML10v2 (a playground/sandpit host of sorts - jumping between Hyper-V and Proxmox) HP PS1810-8G managed switch Some really crappy, locked all-in-one router device thing from my ISP (I cannot remember the model) After FTTC NBN was finally connected - a drama in itself (another long story) - and after deliberating on Point 4, I decided it made sense to opt for something a little more prosumer grade.</description></item><item><title>Building a Site in Gatsby</title><link>https://emdwyer.github.io/2020-07-13-building-a-site-in-gatsby/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>emdwyer</author><guid>https://emdwyer.github.io/2020-07-13-building-a-site-in-gatsby/</guid><description>Here it is in its (relative) infancy! Given the current pandemic unfolding, I decided to complete the following on freeCodeCamp to try and increase my productivity (and employment prospects!) while our city has been in and out of lock down:
Responsive Web Design Certification JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Certification Front End Libraries Certification What this means is, I decided to redo my site using Gatsby, as it seemed to be the static site generator most aligned with React and JavaScript generally, and I was a little curious about GraphQL.</description></item><item><title>First post</title><link>https://emdwyer.github.io/2020-03-20-first/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>emdwyer</author><guid>https://emdwyer.github.io/2020-03-20-first/</guid><description><![CDATA[Well, here it is. I thought I should attempt to start some platform to rant and share things on, tech related and whatnot. So - here&rsquo;s my first blog, which I&rsquo;ll use to share anything related to Linux, development, maybe some fitness and other miscellaneous subjects.
Bear with me, as this site also will also serve as a starting point for (re)learning some web development. For the past few years, I&rsquo;ve largely concentrated on Ruby, C#, some BASH and other scripting &ndash; so I&rsquo;m picking up web again and I&rsquo;m very rusty!]]></description></item></channel></rss>