<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>infosec - Tag - emdwyer</title><link>https://emdwyer.github.io/tags/infosec/</link><description>infosec - Tag - emdwyer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>hello@emdwyer.dev (emdwyer)</managingEditor><webMaster>hello@emdwyer.dev (emdwyer)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://emdwyer.github.io/tags/infosec/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Shoppy HTB Walkthrough</title><link>https://emdwyer.github.io/2023-01-14-shoppy-htb/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>emdwyer</author><guid>https://emdwyer.github.io/2023-01-14-shoppy-htb/</guid><description>Intro I have been spending some time over the holiday break working on CTF challenges - including both Hack The Box, PicoCTF and learning a little binary exploitation. Taking notes for my own review &amp;amp; learning seemed like a good opportunity to post up CTF walkthroughs and get back into the habit of blogging again.
So, here is the first of hopefully many walkthroughs I will post up as time permits, and when machines on Hack The Box are retired.</description></item><item><title>Rebuilding Homelab - Part 1</title><link>https://emdwyer.github.io/2021-03-24-rebuilding-homelab/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>emdwyer</author><guid>https://emdwyer.github.io/2021-03-24-rebuilding-homelab/</guid><description>Cable management - please don't do this. Ever. After relocating around Melbourne multiple times during 2020 (pandemic - long story) and finally settling into my own place with FTTC, I decided it was time to revive the home lab. Previously back in Newcastle, my homelab comprised of:
HP MicroServer Gen 8 (running Proxmox) HP ML10v2 (a playground/sandpit host of sorts - jumping between Hyper-V and Proxmox) HP PS1810-8G managed switch Some really crappy, locked all-in-one router device thing from my ISP (I cannot remember the model) After FTTC NBN was finally connected - a drama in itself (another long story) - and after deliberating on Point 4, I decided it made sense to opt for something a little more prosumer grade.</description></item></channel></rss>